JAVIER NICOLÁS BURGOS

GAMEPLAY PROGRAMMER

- nicolasb813@gmail.com
- elnicoburgos.github.io
- **** +543874192085
- ▼ Tucumán, Argentina
- in elnicoburgos
- C ElNicoBurgos

With an associate degree in Computer Science and nearing completion of my bachelor's, I delved into game development in 2018, exploring tools and concepts independently. My unwavering passion for creating immersive gaming experiences drives me to continuously learn, innovate, and excel in this dynamic field.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

С

C++

C#

Python

SQL

VIDEOGAME SOFTWARE

Unreal Engine 4 & 5

Unity

Construct

UNREAL ENGINE 4 & 5

AI - AI Senses

AI - Behavior Trees

Enviroment Query System (EQS)

Gameplay Ability System (GAS)

Network Multiplayer Programming

Unreal Motion Graphics UI Designer (UMG)

Enhanced Input

Wwise

OTHER TOOLS

Perforce

Subversion

Git

Swarm

Jenkins Jira

EMPLOYMENT

Globant

Gameplay Programmer

Led project setup on Amazon Luna platform for seamless implementation.

Troubleshot technical issues in Unreal Engine 5, optimizing performance.

Spearheaded game porting to mobile platforms and Nintendo Switch.

Expertise in Unreal Engine 5 setup, troubleshooting, and platform porting.

Image Campus

Unreal Engine 5 Teacher

Buenos Aires, Argentina July 2023 to Current

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Sept. 2023 to Current

Delivered engaging lectures, workshops, and hands-on sessions.

Mentored students in projects, fostering creativity and problem-solving

Provided real-world insights from industry experience.

Supported students' career aspirations.

Designed and executed a comprehensive Unreal Engine 5 curriculum covering game mechanics, blueprints, asset creation, and C++.

Nimble Giant Entertainment - Part of Embracer Group

Gameplay Programmer - Unannounced AAA First Person Shooter (FPS) Apr. 2021 to Sept. 2023 Use the Gameplay Ability System(GAS) of Unreal Engine 5.

Build and maintain production-quality gameplay systems, workflows, and tools in C++ on Unreal 5.

Implement server-side gameplay mechanics.

Experience with debugging application.

Gameplay Programmer - Quantum League

Nov. 2020 to Apr. 2021

Implement some abilities (GAS) of characters to work in multiplayer or single-player games.

Involved in efforts to improve the polish of the game through the resolution of various bugs.

Participation in efforts to improve the quality of the code by reviewing the code.

Game fully released on Steam in April 2021.

Last Minute Crew

Generalist Programmer - Öga Project

Tucuman, Argentina Jan. 2020 to July 2021

Contributed to main mechanics design and implementation.

Implemented UI interfaces for a virtual reality game.

Collaborated with designers, artists, and programmers to enhance gameplay.

Utilized Scrum methodology in team projects.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Associate Degree in Software Development

2017 to Current 2017 to Mar. 2021